Guide to the James A. Hayden Photographs and Memorabilia AIA.033
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
James A. Hayden Photographs and Memorabilia
1924-2006
1961-1989
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Hayden, James A.
AIA.033
2.83 Linear Feet in 4 manuscript boxes and 1 custom box
3 videocassettes (vhs)
1 sound tape reels
James A. Hayden (d. 1943) worked as a columnist for the Irish Echo newspaper in the 1930s and early 1940s. Starting in 1928, Hayden also worked as a radio broadcaster, hosting the program Irish Memories at local station WEVD. The James A. Hayden Photographs and Memorabilia collection consists primarily of photographs and negatives collected by Hayden in his capacity as a columnist for the Irish Echo. The photographs include portraits, social and cultural events, as well as groups of people. Additional materials in this collection include some VHS tapes, an audio reel, news clippings and memorabilia. This collection also includes photographs and personal items belonging to Hayden's daughter, Dorothy Hayden Cudahy, and son-in-law, John J. Cudahy.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for researchers without restrictions.
Scope and Contents
The James A. Hayden Photographs and Memorabilia collection consists primarily of photographs and negatives collected by Hayden in his capacity as a columnist for the Irish Echo. The photographs include portraits, social and cultural events, as well as groups of people. Additional materials in this collection include some VHS tapes, an audio reel, news clippings, and memorabilia.
This collection also includes photographs featuring Dorothy Hayden Cudahy and John J. Cudahy, their honeymoon notebook, an audio reel entitled "D. Cudahy," and John Cudahy's elementary school diploma and award.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The provenance of materials found in this collection are unknown.
Arrangement
The materials in this collection are arranged in alphabetical order.
Related Materials
Dorothy Hayden Cudahy Papers (AIA.001)
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Biographical Note
James A. Hayden (d. 1943) worked as a columnist for the Irish Echo newspaper in the 1930s and early 1940s. Starting in 1928, Hayden also worked as a radio broadcaster, hosting the program Irish Memories at local station WEVD. After Hayden's death in 1943, his daughter, Dorothy Hayden Cudahy, became the host of Irish Memories until 1990. Dorothy Hayden Cudahy married John J. Cudahy in 1947 and they went on to have one son, Sean, in 1950.
Photographs.; Correspondence.; VHS; Audiovisual materials.; Negatives (photographs); Ireland.; Florida.; New York (N.Y.).; award; Cudahy, Dorothy Hayden, 1922-2010; Cudahy, John J., 1920-1994
- Catholic Saint Medal - St. Patrick, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence - to Dorothy Cudahy (with photos), 1992 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence - to Dorothy and John Cudahy, 1948, 1963-1964, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- D. Hayden, undated (Box Shared Tamiment 088, Quarter inch audio reel 033_0004)
- Framed Painting of Two Children, undated (Box Shared Tamiment 163)
- Graduation Exercises -St. Margaret's School, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Graduation Exercises -- St. Margaret's School -- General Excellence Award, 1962 (Box Shared Tamiment 163)
- John Cudahy, The Builders, New York The Way It Was, undated (Box Shared Tamiment 088, Vhs 033_0002)
- Newspaper Clipping - "School Children March in Hayden Funeral", undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- "Our Honeymoon" - Dorothy and John, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Photo Negatives, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Photo Negatives - Cudahy, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Photographs, 1944, 1961, 1963, 1968, 1975-1976, 1980, 1989, 1994-1995, undated (Box 1, Folder 9-10, Box 2, Folder 1)
- Photographs - Cudahy, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Photographs - Dorothy Hayden Cudahy, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Photographs - Holiday Cards, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Photographs - James A. Hayden, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Photographs - J.C.C., 1988 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Photograph - John J. Cudahy Grave, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Photographs - Photo Album, 1980, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Photograph - Portrait of a Young Boy, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Photographs - Scenery and Negs, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Photographs - Scrapbook, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Photographs - Sean and Family, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Photographs and Photo Negatives, 1987, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Photographs and Photo Negatives - Dorothy and John Cudahy, 1947, 1977, 1979, 1984, 1989, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Photographs and Photo Negatives - from John J. Cudahy, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
- St. Patrick's Day Parade, 2006 (Box Shared Tamiment 088, Vhs 033_0003)
- St. Patrick Parade, Rockaway, 1986 (Box Shared Tamiment 088, Vhs 033_0001)